### McCann Dahl

Dallas, Texas 75409 • (469) 964-8911 mccdahl@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/mccanndahl

### **Executive Summary**

As a passionate technology expert with 5 years of enterprise consulting experience. I've driven teams to assess, design, implement and refine IT products across 4 different industries. I currently manage a team of developers, testers, product managers, and contractors at a major airline with a contract of over \$2M/yr estimated revenue this year. In the past I've been part of a larger team consulting for a hedge fund, helping them set up their IT branch and infrastructure, bringing in over \$4M/yr in revenue. My strengths are connecting with others and driving teams to the finish line with quality.

### **Highlights**

- 6 years of consulting experience with IT c-suite executives in 5 industries
- 15 years of software development experience
- Saved my client from making another \$800 million disaster by managing a team that optimized and modernized their IT infrastructure
- Won an international XR hackathon by gathering and leading a team of engineers to build a Microsoft Hololens application for construction workers
- Special olympics coach for 8 years

# **Professional Experience**

### Pariveda Solutions, Dallas TX Associate II

08/2022-Present

When a major airline company had a terrible winter season filled with thousands of canceled flights and lost crew members, I led a team of engineers to transform part of an antiquated monolithic on-prem infrastructure into an event-driven scalable cloud system. This resulted in 95% fewer canceled flights and 88% time savings for "return to normal" operations.

- Managed a team of 8 (2 consultants, 2 offshore contractors, 1 associate, and 1 client project manager, 2 testers)
- Directed pods that serviced multiple platforms focused on automating cloud solutions between different core business systems
- Architectured a notification cloud solution for a major airline to send 100s of SMS and Email flight updates to crew members
- Drove end-to-end delivery of several key epics related to crew logistics
- Lead status meetings with key stakeholders communicating milestones, risks, and mitigation strategies
- Planned and delegated epics, features, and stories to teams
- Coordinated and tracked inter-team dependencies & risks
- Created a business model canvas and value justification framework to focus the account on delivering value

Associate I 06/2021-08/2022

A lumber manufacturing client believed having technology products would make it easier for customers to purchase their products. I became certified as a cloud solutions architect then helped move their monolithic products into microservices.

- Managed a team of 2 developers in the manufacturing industry to create a product that automates lumber distribution & supply chain logistics
- Architected many microservices leveraging cloud technologies and infrastructure-as-code
- Identified client needs and process-based bottlenecks using the flow framework
- Continuously sold services to partner consulting firms in all aspects of the project planning (research, recommendations, design, implementation)

# Pariveda Solutions, Dallas TX Consultant II

12/2019-06/2021

A hedge fund had just divested from its parent company and was in need of consulting services to help them create IT infrastructure that would service their investors and accounting specialists.

- Managed the implementation of an SQL Server Enterprise Data Warehouse, full-stack (Angular/.Net) custom internal financial system, and automated reporting solutions. These systems were used by various technology and financial teams to examine and forecast the risk and performance of multi-million dollar investments
- Designed self-service tools for large-scale data integrity robotic process automation
- Worked with multiple data vendors to provide profitable datasets used in daily combined-source reports
- Trained business users on custom software solutions and documented business logic
- Provided high-quality business analysis by proposing automation & self-service tools that replaced manual workflows. Worked with both business and IT to translate issues, align priorities, and create feature schedules
- Trained IT members on CI/CD process on Azure, release management in multiple environments, and agile best practices

# Pariveda Solutions, Fort Worth TX Consultant I

05/2019-12/2019

A healthcare company that sells different kinds of insurance was on a tight deadline to develop a recommendation system before open enrollment. I was put on an implementation team with the goal of finishing a lot of work under a tight deadline. I took initiative to create an automated test suite that drastically helped us meet this deadline.

- Developed frontend Direct-to-Consumer web application for a large insurance provider. This application
  used a wizard and prediction algorithm to recommend the most beneficial insurance plan from various
  companies
- Presented team demos of new features (including mobile functionality) to key business stakeholders
- Facilitated development team retrospectives, estimation meetings, and sprint planning meetings using agile scrum methodology practices
- Coordinated story creation and requirements gatherings from business analysts and marketing teams
- Created a new automated test framework for the web application using Selenium, leading to a substantial 80% reduction in testing time

### Deloitte & Touche LLP, Seattle WA Technology Management Consultant

05/2018-08/2018

- Streamlined client's tax management by strategically implementing enterprise technologies
- Implemented scalable solutions to match client's needs and improve business growth
- Designed and developed a custom dashboard to show the results of tax reporting from various financial systems
- Automated tax engines called robotics to make tax reporting faster and more efficient

# Lingotek Cloud-Based Translation, Lehi UT Software Engineer

04/2018-08/2018

- Coded both frontend and backend using MySQL databases and PHP
- Integrated the Lingotek services into the popular connector called Drupal
- Organized and managed monthly sprints and code releases while designing, problem-solving, and debugging

### **Education**

B.S. in Mechanical Engineering (2019) Brigham Young University, Provo UT

# **Technologies & Certifications**

Languages: C#, C, Javascript, Typescript, SQL, C++, Dart, Python, PHP, HTML, CSS, VBA, Java

Databases: MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Aurora Postgres

API Frameworks: ASP .NET, .NET Core, NodeJS, Flask, Django, FastAPI, Express

Web: React, Angular, Vue, Drupal

Mobile: Android, Flutter, Kivy, React Native

Cloud Services: Amazon AWS - Solutions Architect Associate, Microsoft ADO, Jira, Google Analytics,

Serverless